# **HENRIQUE FREITAS SOUZA**

### UI/UX DESIGNER

### **PROFILE**

Phone +55 011 95435-5406

E-mail henrique@henriquefreitas.com.br

Portfolio henriquefreitas.com.br

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/henriquefreitassouza

Address Taboão da Serra, SP. Brazil

### PITCH

I'm a UI/UX designer who wrote many lines of code and worked at Fortune 100 companies. Today I research, build and test new ideas for web and mobile products and analyze data to generate useful insights on how to improve user experience.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Conversion Chef | UI/UX Designer 2016 - Now

I create and test hypotheses based on data collected through the CRO process, perform A/B tests and heuristic analysis, design information architectures and redesign websites.

- Learned the fundamentals of CRO
- · First UI/UX professional at the company

#### Nestlé | Project Manager 2014 - 2015

Managed infrastructure projects and represented Brazil as cloud solutions coordinator. Implemented and managed the cloud security process; managed CAPEX execution.

- 3 projects delivered
- · 15 cloud security controls applied

#### Addbiz | Full Stack Developer 2010 - 2013

Designed and created UIs and graphic assets for hotsites, banners and e-mail marketing campaigns for an e-commerce. Developed hotsites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, PHP, MySQL and SQL Server.

- Learned much about many modern technologies
- Deployed hotsites for an e-commercd with 200.000+ users/month

## **EDUCATION**

#### Designer | Gama Academy

2016

5 weeks course immersed in the startup ecossystem along with successfull CEOs and designers to learn the required soft and hard skills to work at startups.

- One of the 100 selected over 5412 candidates
- 3rd in the rank of best design students

#### Information Systems | FIAP

2012 - 2015

Bachelor's degree.